# Qinyun (Devina) Fan

Product Management | MVP | G2M | Roadmap | SaaS | B2B | B2C | Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

Illinois, U.S. ● <u>devinafqy@outlook.com</u> ● 919-6382814 ● Portfolio: <u>https://www.devina-fan-portfolio.com/</u>

#### SUMMARY

A Strategic Product Manager with 3 years of experience in Go-to-Market Strategies, addressing customer pain points and launching B2C/B2B products. My journey includes co-founding an ed-tech startup and scaling its market valuation by 240%, leading to a successful \$300k exit. I'm now leading 3 primary projects for Illinois DCFS initiative, transitioning a 30-year legacy system to a \$400M valued SaaS product. At Unilever, I spearheaded product marketing initiatives that surged sales by over 50%. I'm now seeking a PM position where I bring my G2M and B2C product launch to support your strategic goal.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Duke University, Fugua School of Business**

Durham, U.S.A

Master of Management Studies in Foundation of Business and Quantitative Method (STEM), 3.65/4.00

July 2022 - May 2023

• Equivalent to First Year DUKE MBA; <u>Courses</u>: Supply Chain Analysis, Financial Analysis, Strategy Analysis, Decision and Modeling **Emerson College**Boston, U

Bachelor of Science in Marketing Communication, 3.98/4.00

**Boston, U.S.A** Sept 2018 – May 2021

Honors: Summa Cum Laude, 2020 Gold Key Honor Society (top 1%), Dean's List for six semesters (Graduated in 3 years)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Illuminative Strategies, Product/Process Optimization Engineer, Consultant I, Springfield, IL 07/2023-Present Achievements

- Transitioning a 30-year-old legacy system to a B2B SaaS product for a \$400M 6-year state agency (Illinois DCFS) project, which led to a 70% uptick in operational efficiency and reduced client's manual effort by 95% for current release.
- Leading process redesigns and product implementations for 3 worksteams and oversees agile product cycles in Jira, boosting sprint completion rates by 18% and achieving a 10% reduction in cross-vendor discrepancies with 40+ stakeholders.

# Responsibilities

- Leading the process optimization component of the B2B SaaS MVP, which addressed 300+ process and system pain points.
- Writing **user stories** for the B2B SaaS product by co-establishing backlogs to improve feature adoptions.
- Collected **VOC** by conducting 40+ current state Swimlane process mapping sessions to **prioritize product requirements**.
- Defining **KPIs** like process lead time, cycle time, WIP, etc. through process lean assessment of 450+ steps using lean six sigma methodologies, to analyze performance metrics and institute data-driven decision-making.
- Managing a team of 3 and collaborating cross functionally with a team of 38 across engineers, communication team, multiple vendor parties
  and clients.

# MECAMP, Head of Product, Startup Co-Founder, 2/2020-3/2022

### **Achievements**

- Co-founded a business-focused educational institution, leveraging advanced analytics to increase market valuation by 240% within two years, resulting in a successful \$300k sale.
- Achieved a student recruitment rate of 350+ within 1 year by implementing data-driven feedback mechanism, ensuring a 20% rise in student satisfaction scores and enhanced course relevance.
- Designed and launched "Entrepreneurship" Series from foundational 100 courses to advanced 300 series, incorporating tech-based learning tools and a scalable content framework, achieving a 20% success rate of students launching startups post-completion.

#### Responsibilities

- Established **product roadma**p for a 10+ business curriculum focusing span from finance, economics, and entrepreneurship, integrating LMS and e-learning technologies.
- Gathered **VOC** through 40+feedback sessions with students, employing Agile frameworks to rapidly iterate on course content and introduce high-demand modules, leading to a 15% increase in enrollment.
- Defined and monitored course **KPIs**, analyzing student success rates, course feedback, and post-course career trajectories to ensure continuous curriculum improvement and relevance.
- Led cross-functional collaboration with a team of 12 across marketing, sales and teaching to launch an MVP focused on socially responsible marketing strategies and promote the integration of ethical business practices.

# **Unilever** *Product Marketing, Brand Building Marketing Intern*, Shanghai, China 11/2021-3/2022 **Achievements**

- Managed end-to-end process from ideation to marketing deployment for Clear's B2C e-commerce product relaunch for Clear during 618 Shopping Festival, leading over 50% sales growth compared to the previous year.
- Launched an MVP test for Lifebuoy's B2C e-commerce product by initiating social seedings on Little Red Book (China's Instagram), which resulted in a 29.8% surge in engagement and a 12% average click-through rate within 5 months, and produced 420+ social postings that led to 3 viral articles amassing 200k+ views through data-driven strategies and influencer collaboration.

# Responsibilities

- Developed **go-to-market strategy** for Clear/Lifebuoy's B2C personal wash retail products by focusing on key digital touchpoints, such as display booth designs, e-commerce strategies, and points of sale materials to maximize product visibility and sales.
- Captured **VOC** through targeted promotions, and led agency pitches for Clear's product designs by managing 80+ content creators, ensuring prioritized and aligned product messaging to enhance ROI.
- Spearheaded Clear's Y22 creative productions, achieving 16.7% savings on the ¥120k budget through negotiation and vendor management.

• Led team of 14 on product relaunch shooting and retouching, producing 12 KVs and one 15s-TVC within a tight 2-week deadline.

# Research Square Company, Product Market Researcher, Part-time Consultant, Durham, NC 10/2022-3/2023 Achievements

• Leveraged findings from 35 in-depth **VOC** interviews to fine-tune **go-to-market strategy** and designed 4 buyer journeys for both B2C and B2B segments, instrumental in achieving a 33% growth in memberships within 6 months.

#### Responsibilities

- Charted **product roadmap** for B2C AI-powered scientific writing assistant consumer product and delivered 2 presentations for C-Cuite, pinpointing product-market fit and market variations.
- Undertook in-depth market research for the product to gauge market size using SQL and assess competitive landscape using AB testing.
- Collaborated closely with a team of 8 across product and marketing teams, facilitating actionable insights from research finding to influence product development.

# VOLUNTEER and LEADERSHIP

# Shanghai Animal Rescue Centre Board Member

Shanghai, China/Remote May. 2015 – Current

- Served as Foster Caregiver for 7 years; Served as Flight Volunteers for 4 years.
- Incubated and operated an online influencer account on Chinese TikTok through video editing, content creation, live streaming, and e-commerce in 2020, gaining 3M+ viewers in 2 months; the account now values \$35k+, with 450k+ followers.

# **SKILLS and INTERESTS**

- Product Management Skills: Product Roadmap, G2M, MIS, B2C, B2B, G2M, VOC Research, SaaS, KPI, User Stories, Buyer Persona, Customer Interviews, Product Demo, Communication Skills, Project Management, Confluence
- Technical Skills: Figma, Modeling Software (MS Excel, SQL, R Studio), Video Editing (Final Cut Pro), SAP, Visio, A/B Testing, MS PowerPoint, Jira
- Certification: Lean Six Sigma Black Belt
- Languages: Mandarin (Native), English (Professional), French (Beginner)
- Interests: Vlogger, Film /Theatre Appreciation, Poker, Dog Training